Preliminary Guide to the Edgemont Community Center Records, 1955-1973
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Edgemont Community Center records 1955-1973
Edgemont Community Center
6 linear feet Extent: 2500 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.00351
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the Rubenstein Library to use this collection.
Provenance
Received as a gift by the Rare Book, Manuscript and Special Collections Library in 1973.
Historical Note
The Edgemont Community Center was incorporated in 1941 in Durham, NC, as an autonomous, service oriented center located in a low-income white neighborhood beset by numerous social problems. The center came to serve a more racially mixed population in later years.
Subject Headings
Edgemont Community Center; Edgemont Community -- Durham, (N.C.); Community development, Urban -- North Carolina -- Durham; Durham (N.C.) -- Social conditions; Community centers -- Durham (N.C.)
Contents of Collection
- Accession 72-044
  This unprocessed accession of administrative records documents the operations, fund raising activities, programs, and publications of the Durham based service organization between 1955 and 1973, chiefly 1967-1973. The collection is open for research.
  - Correspondence, 1967-1973 (Box 1)
  - Announcements, 1967-1973 and undated (Box 1)
  - Board of Director - Organization, various dates and undated (Box 1)
  - By-laws, various dates and undated (Box 1)
  - Clinic, undated (Box 1)
  - Clippings, various dates (Box 1)
  - Director's Reports, 1965-1970 (Box 1)
  - Director's Reports, 1970-1973 (Box 1)
  - Financial Statements, 1955-1972 (Box 1)
  - Financial Statements, 1972-1973 and undated (Box 1)
  - Forms, 1968 and undated (Box 1)
  - Ledger, 1959-1964 (Box 2)
  - Ledger, 1957-1968 (Box 2)
  - Legal Papers, 1941-1963 and undated (Box 3)
  - Fund Raising: Special Programs, 1967-1967 and undated (Box 3)
  - Funding Proposals and Sources, 1967-1973 and undated (Box 3)
  - Insurance, 1965-1971 and undated (Box 3)
  - Minutes, 1944-1969 and undated (Box 3)
  - Minutes, 1969-1973 and undated (Box 3)
  - Property, 1955-1968 and undated (Box 3)
  - Property for Reorganization, 1969 and undated (Box 3)
  - Pictures, 1971 and undated (Box 3)
  - Proposal Endorsements, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Summer Programs, 1967-1973 and undated (Box 4)
  - The Torch, 1,1 - 2,5: 1970, Oct. 15-1972, Dec. 10 (Box 4)
  - SE Durham Recreation & Youth Activities: A Task Force Report, 1972, Aug. (Box 4)
  - United Fund, 1964-1969 and undated (Box 4)
  - General, 1967-1972 and undated (Box 4)
  - Papers, 1950-1973, (2 folders) (Box 4)